security and the low carbon transformation continuing from the previous session this
lecture will focus on power grade security management supporting technical solutions
for carbon emission reduction under high new energy penetration rate if you have industrial
related questions please raise your hand for the q and a at the end of the lecture please welcome
Welcome, Professor Zhang.
OK, I'm very glad to communicate with you.
And during my speech, if you have any questions,
you can use any kind of questions.
OK, the next topic is for the new type of power system
security and low carbon transformation.
And we will divide it into two parts.
The first part is for the security.
What kind of security we have to do this for the new kind of cloud system?
And the next part is for the collaborative completion of the source network load, storage, and guest hub.
So this was the first part of the new cloud system security.
I don't understand that.
In the last section of the lecture, we have already summarized the characteristics of the new step of the power system.
That is how to convey efficient consumption and make a stable operation through high proportion of the renewable energy and high proportion of the power electronics.
How to operate it? How to make the power system to be operated, to be stable operation?
This is one difficult problem.
And another difficult problem is that a large number of power electronic devices are widely integrated into the system.
And such kind of power electronic devices will be active very fast, in milliseconds or microseconds.
So fast regulation of the power electronics will make the power system initially become weaker and weaker.
So this is the second difficulty.
And then China will encounter another continuous load growth.
So our power, electricity consumption will be doubled compared with now, with 2035.
And it will be doubled until 2050. The total consumption will be doubled.
And this doubled power generation, maybe 100% of this double increased amount will be achieved by the renewable energy.
But for the remaining, for the stable remaining generation is still a lot of, a large percentage of the remaining power requirements also will be substituted by the new energy.
So how to meet the consumer's needs and how to meet the user requirements for the high quality of power plants.
So this is also a very difficult task for the next year because the durability and the power quality will affect the Chinese economy very, very seriously.
For example, last year, in Shanghai, there was a big company to produce chips.
It encountered a power set and encountered a lot of losses, economic damage for the production.
We think that such kind of enterprises, such kind of users will become, increasingly become
larger and larger.
So the power quality, power reliability will be a very serious problem for China.
And the last difficulty is that in the conventional, coal-fired power plants are gradually reduced.
And finally, the power plant proportion, the coal-fired power plant proportion will reduce
to 20%, or less than 20%.
And this 20% of coal-fired power plants will be reformed by the low carbon, will be reformed
by the new technology, for example, the carbon capture, and so on.
So we encounter so many difficulties on how to make a reliable operation of the new power system.
And this is the security problem in the surveillance service.
So we summarize the six securities.
The first is for the system security.
That is how to prevent the large scale power outage for the power system.
This is the system security.
The second one is network and information security.
There's a cyber attack, how to prevent a cyber attack.
For example, in China, the authorities,
when every year, the authorities will issue
remote cyber attack to each substations,
to each substations.
Every attack will defeat some transformational systems.
And the third one is personal safety.
That is, every year there is a personal death by the electricity.
And the fourth one is equipment safety.
How to maintain the equipment to be safely operating.
And another one is the electric, the so-called electrical systems, the environmental systems,
and some low-voltage, low-voltage systems, that is the user, user-compatible, because
a lot of distributed PV connected to the lower network, how to maintain the safety of the
low-voltage systems.
So the sixth security system is encountered by our power system planners and power system creators.
And the first one is the system security.
So as what we said, we have encountered such a complex, such a complex, such a high proportion of renewable energy over the power system.
how to maintain the system to be operated with reliability and safety.
Because of the reliability and the intensity of the high proportion of the energy,
we have to make a balance every time.
And the power electronics makes the system initial to be reduced very fast.
And then the load characteristics become changed to the power constant.
So the load is very sensitive to the voltage fluctuations.
So this means that the operation to maintain the voltage is quite difficult.
And the last one is that the proportion of the electricity received outside the urban,
outside the big city, becomes larger and larger.
So the city, especially in Shanghai and Beijing, such a big city,
encounters risk for the reactive power collapse, for the voltage collapse.
So this voltage has already occurred in the western countries,
for example in London, in Paris, in the western of the United States,
they encountered several system outages for the voltage collapse.
That is that you have less reactive power support,
so that if there is a short circuit in the high voltage system,
the reactive power becomes very, very, very short.
So the voltage becomes collapsed.
So just like London, like Paris, and the Western, the Silicon,
the Western United States, all of these developed countries
encounter the voltage collapse.
So this is our encounter.
So we have to pay more attention to the system security, and such a large-scale power outage
occasionally occurs frequently, for example, in Brazil, I don't know if someone from Brazil
experienced a major blackout in 2018, and due to the protection of sighting areas.
For example, Argentina, in 2019, they also encountered massive blackouts.
For example, in 2022, a large-scale power outage occurred in Taiwan.
And this also makes the user loss a lot of loads.
And the United Kingdom, and also typhoon, super typhoon, affect the Hainan province.
And such large-scale outage belongs to the system safety, because it belongs to the high
outage, or over-high outage system, to encounter some short-scale, encounter some outage, and
result in a large-scale outage of the users.
And we have to encounter such a problem, we have to use, to solve the power system security
security through intelligent means. For example, in the state grid, we use a lot of intelligent
dispatching for the power system. Just as what I said, we reduce the period of the decision,
dispatching decisions, from 15 minutes to maybe 10 minutes to 5 minutes, and then we
use the intelligent dispatching of power system to reduce the outage of the power system.
This is one. Technology uses the intelligent means to solve, to increase the power system, the system's security.
For example, we use the flexible dynamic adjustment of the source, storage and load.
And this is also another mean to avoid the system failure.
And we use the safety means of the energy storage system,
energy storage, how to safely operate it for the storage.
And we use the rapid protection and self-hearing of the grid,
especially for the distribution grid.
For example, the short-circuit characteristics have changed a lot.
In the past, the short-circuit just formed one side,
from the power stations. But now there is a lot of distributed PV connected into the
end of the power lines. So the sub-circuit characteristics become changed.
So the protection principle has already changed. So we have to make rapid protection.
We make the self-carrying of the grid, especially for the distribution grid.
And also we use the robots to operate with the electricity.
We use the helicopter, we use the robots to make the maintenance, to make the maintenance of the power lines.
We use the virtual power plants to make the balance between the source and the load,
so that we can also make the balance of the system, to avoid the system outage.
and we also use the flexible interconnection between or among several
distribution stations. We use the DC, flexible DC to connect each distribution
to make the balance of each distribution stations. And this
means, all of this means, aim to solve the power system security. So this one
one kind of security program.
Another security program is a network,
a network on information security in the system.
For example, in ,
there is a big outage in for 2019.
There is a attack, information attack
into a major hydroplot plant in this country,
and then result in the outage of the whole country.
So after this outage, the Chinese government gave a lot of notice,
a lot of attention to that kind of war.
So from that outage, from that time,
the Chinese government asked the enterprises to take notice of the information security,
to make isolation between the system information and the offline.
So that the power grid information security will direct or indirectly affect the whole power system,
the whole security of the power system.
So we think that the information security threat may exist in every stage of the generation,
distribution, transmission, distribution, transformation, and the users.
So once this kind of attack affects the power station, affects the power system, they make
a very large disaster.
So we think every year, the Chinese government will issue a simulated attack to the stations.
stations, and every attack will destroy several stations. So this is a very serious problem.
So the information attack comes from two sides. One side comes from the external, comes from
the outside of our system. For example, the hacker attack. For example, the virus infects.
For example, the social engineering attacks, that is, some enemies who ask to make some
mis-operations.
This is from the outside, especially from hackers.
I think a lot of countries have already encountered such a hacker attack to the power system.
For example, in Russia, in many European countries, there is a hacker attack, in China also.
Another threat is from the inside, the internal information attack threat.
That is, employees miss operations.
They close the switches and make the information miss operations.
So this kind of attack affects the information system.
So we have to make an optimized operation of the power system itself and the information system.
So this has to be coordinated, operated with each other.
So the power system integrated with the information system
will support the conventional optimization of the source grid load and storage.
We use several technological innovation to promote the safety and stable operation.
How to solve this one?
We have to strengthen the cyber security measures
to ensure the security of the process network and information.
So, in China, the grid has developed specialized security chips, and these chips will be installed
in each awareness devices, the data collected devices, in the following five years.
And each, for example, each meter, each wireless device, data collecting system, or SCAR system,
and each device will be installed with such special security chips to make the information
secure.
And this is one measure.
Another matter is to make the secondary system to be safely protected, for example, the information
system, the communication system, the protection system.
We make the whole system to make a cascade of information security protection.
And also, every year we have a simulated attack to make us transfer for the information security
to attack, to make a simulation attack, to check whether or not it is safe.
And the last measure is to make a training, to make a network security training.
Every year we make the information operators to be trained every year and to be security.
So this is a measure to strengthen cyber security.
The third safety problem is personal safety.
Personal safety is personal accidents that occur every year.
So, maybe last meeting we have a summary, every year the China power system maybe make a tax about 50 to 100.
So, for example, the tower collapse of the federal system, the equipment hazard,
for example, the accident caused by electric leakage, for example, caused by the lands, and so on.
So, in our government, we pay a lot of attention to personal safety.
But how to ensure the personal safety, that is the strength and safety supervision for the personnel in the path of safety?
We have a shift from the post-event to proactive prevention.
We have to make the supervision measures shift from rigid to flexible regulations.
We have to make the investment to shift from the administrative bottom land protection to the cost-reduced and efficient improvement.
We have to make a safety supervision the responsibility to shift from the being on vigor to a very
clear determinant.
So this kind of technology could be used to prevent the personal death from the safety.
So we use the innovative technology means for the safety supervision.
For example, the Internet of Things.
We use this technology to process
class, process algorithms, process the
technical monitoring. So, they make the full process
supervision for the front, middle, and back end
of the project. So, every project in the Neon Science
they install several monitoring
monitoring, supervision to make the personal safety.
So this is in the Chinese power, power integrates,
enterprises, we use to supervise,
to monitor the personal safety.
So this is another one.
So we use a traditional manner inspection.
infection, this infection will be graduated, upgraded by automatic, visualized, intelligent
operations and maintenance. By utilizing technologies such as artificial intelligence, the internet
of things, digital tools, and augmented reality, we use such technologies to prevent, to make
the personal safety become. And we have to through the frequent and comprehensive training
and drills, the personal skill levels of our system operation and maintenance could be enhanced.
So every year we make a lot of training projects to enhance the operators,
to change their safety manner, to change their safety still.
And the fourth one is for the equipment safety.
Every equipment safety is caused by fire, by earthquake, by another.
For example, our storage station, especially for the chemical storage station,
will be constructed in the future, and how to defend, how to prevent the fire disaster.
So the fire disasters occur occasionally in the Chinese fire station.
For example, maybe in 2023, there is a fire and explosion accident at Shanxi Brunei
for upper high voltage station.
And also, personally, the offshore wind power installation
encountered many equipment collapse.
For example, in the offshore installation for the wind generators,
this collapsed.
So how to maintain the safety for the equipment,
this is a very serious problem.
So, we use the maintenance, the safety of the power system equipment through technological
implementation.
For example, we make the accurate identification for the insulator defector defects.
We use a drone, air, ground monitor of the transmission land, helicopter, unmanned helicopter and associated with the unmanned operators.
Recently, the state government has issued a satellite, so we use the space, we use air
and ground, the three divisions of the inspection to make the safety of the equipment.
We use the audio visual fusion monitoring for the equipment defects, for example the
inside the transformer for the discharge.
For such kind of discharge, it is very difficult to be detected.
So we use audio-visual fusion technologies to check the discharge inside the transformer.
We use intelligent monitoring for the substations and infrared temperature measurement for the inspection.
And also, we use a radar modeling for the electrical equipment to make a safety maintenance.
And for the cable fault, we make a diagnosis, an intensive diagnosis,
based on the online analysis of sulfur hexafluoride equipment first, based on the leakage of the SF6.
So, all of these measures are made to maintain the safety of the system equipment.
So, this is another kind of security.
And the fifth security is the low voltage system.
We can see that in the past, the low voltage is only a positive system.
But now it becomes active because there is a lot of distributed PV installed in the end
of the low voltage system.
So this makes the personal security very serious.
So a lot of interconnected of the distributed PV to make the overvoltage of the low voltage
system better.
For example, our voltage standard is 220 volts, but if there is distributed PV to be connected
to the end of the low-voltage system, the highest voltage will be higher than 240 volts.
This becomes over-voltage for the appliance, for the personnel safety.
So the power quality issue such as voltage dip, voltage set, and harmonics will also cause the production stop or damage.
So this accident occurs very frequently in the Chinese power system.
And so we have to make the safety operational leakage protection for the low voltage systems.
So in Chinese they will research on the very cheap device to detect the low voltage systems.
security. So we transfer the high tech of the equipment, high technology of the
measures to be shifted to the low voltage to make the monitor of the low voltage.
So this is another security program. So the last one, okay, so we have to
strengthen the publication of the education of the electricity safety for
for all citizens, and this is not the responsibility of the power system utility, but it is the
social responsibility for this.
So the Chinese power utilities have the social responsibility to educate, to train the citizens
to enhance their detection affairs.
And we have to develop the cost effective,
the low cost, and the practical sensor chips
to shift this high tech technology
to the low voltage system.
So in China, I believe, we have to develop
a lot of such kind of chips.
For example, this chip is only very low cost to be installed into the low voltage leakage
and so on.
We have used several devices such as DVR, dynamic voltage regulator, and active filter
to be used in the user side to change to improve the power quality. So all of
this in fact is a means to solve the low voltage system. And the last one is the
environmental safety. So we have some research and development for the
environmental monitoring to develop some several chips to detect the leakage of
the SF6 and the research and development of the new environmental friendly isolation materials
to make some substitutions and also we make a monitor of the electromagnetic
environmental programs and also we make a monitor and control the transformer noise
and for the for the engineering side there is a noise and then dust how to prevent how to monitor
This is also what we have noticed on the nuclear power system.
In 2020-2024, the CPC Central Committee held a collective study session on the new energy technology and how to maintain the Chinese nuclear safety.
And our professor from my university has been sent to give a lecture, give an explanation
to the colleagues of the CPC to make them make a higher professional of the energy safety.
So he said that energy safety is closely tied to the overall development of the economy
economy and the society. We must make the great efforts to promote the high quality
development of the new energy and provide a safety and reliable energy guarantee for
the Chinese-style modernization. So this is to become a very high level for the leaders
to notice for the energy system.
Okay, so we summarized the six areas of the system to make the node case.
And the second part is that we have to make a collective operation of the source, network,
the load, storage, and not the gas, the wiser, the gas.
Did I translate it? It's the wrong translation.
We have to make a collaborative operation of the source, load, grid, storage, and also
plus weather and carbon.
So we think that weather and carbon is two very important things for the new power system
to be noticed in the operation and in the planning of the maintenance.
First of all, the distribution network has already changed a lot.
The past positive distribution network has already changed to active distribution network,
because a large scale of integration of the distributed PV has been connected into the power system,
into the distribution of our system, and a lot of energy storage, distributed energy storage
interconnected into the distribution system.
So the distribution system, the characteristics, the features of the distribution system have changed a lot.
In the past, this system, this distributed system is passive, has no source.
The system has no source. Only source is from the substation, from the big grid.
But the distributed PV and distributed storage have changed the operation scenario of the traditional distribution of systems.
So we call that the modern system is the active distribution network, that's ADN.
And ADN and microgrid and virtual power plants, based on energy internet, are driving the
traditional distributed network to be transferred from the traditional into a new type of the
system.
So we have encountered such transactions.
So this is a traditional, traditional, there is no distributed PV, no active control for
such a distribution system.
So that in Chinese, a lot of Chinese distribution systems, they have no active dispatching,
they have no process operation by means to maintain the distribution system to be operated
seriously.
safety. But notice the system have already changed. It has already changed with
distributed PV, with distributed storage system. And such kind of distributed system have to enhance their active control level.
So the system will gradually transfer from passive to active. So we gradually enter the high penetration of the
PV, distributed PV, high penetration of the distributed storage, and we make active control
for the power source and load.
So the modern distribution system becomes the active distribution system, ADN.
So the international organizations have already made ADN as a standard development, a future
standard of the distribution system.
So this means that the smart equipment, smart control, automation, distribution automation and the user interaction inside the distributed system.
So we encountered a step in the new kind of modern distribution systems.
And such active distribution systems, how to manage them, how to operate.
So this is a very big problem for our new power system operators.
So a lot of hardware devices, such as relay protection, the type changes of the transformers,
automatic voltage regulator for the distributed system, and stat cards, and power factor controllers,
reactive power, adjusters, all of these devices are being installed, are being operated,
cooperated with distributed PV, with the distributed storage system,
and along with all of these modern devices,
it can make the active distribution system to be operated safely.
So this is a very big group of people who made a lot of international standards for such hardware, automatic hardware.
So the second one is how to cooperate the operation and control of the main grid,
that means the high voltage grid, and the distribution line, the medium voltage grid, and the microgrid, so the low voltage grid.
It makes the coordinate operation for the three kinds of grain.
In the past, the state grain, the Chinese power utilities only managed for the main grain
and paid less attention to the distribution grain and paid no attention to the macro grain.
But nowadays, the idea has already changed.
So the city council has already issued a document to maintain the coordinate operation for the
main grid, distributed grid, and the microgrid.
So how to interconnect the main grid and make the intergrids of the main distribution and
micro upgrade to provide guarantee for the coordinated development of the power
system. This is a big problem for our operations. For the main grid, we have to
use interconnected centralized monitoring system for the new energy
station for the concentrated wind power station, concentrated PV
PV stations to make monitoring, to make the operation monitoring, to make the intelligent
operations and the maintenance, to make the operational decision making, and so on.
So that the main power grid pays more attention to this one, and it has also paid attention
to the lower level of the voltage system.
For example, the main grid dispatching system
has to consider how the requirement
from the distribution system.
What is the requirement from the micro grid?
So we have to complete it for the three kinds of work.
And we have to develop a new distribution automation system.
So for the distributed grid,
Our regional distribution network has to be transparently monitored.
We have installed a lot of awareness devices to collect data, operation data, from the end of the distribution network
to achieve active balance control for the source, for the grid, for the load and storage.
So the transparent monitoring is very important for the distribution system.
So, based on the various types of equipment, we have developed a lot of devices, such as
primary and secondary integrated terminals, intelligent terminals, and developed four
project lines of the smart distribution terminals based on independently controllable technology.
So such kind of terminals have already installed or will be installed in the end of the distribution system
to make the distribution system more transparently monitored, to make it more controllable.
And for the microgrid, the microgrid will be balanced for the load side.
The microgrid is also in the load side.
We have to ensure the balance, the stable, the efficient, the economic operation of the microgrid
to promote the consumption of the utilization of the distributed PV.
So we think that the microgrid is a balanced manner.
So we use the intelligent microgrid to coordinate the devices
devices, and the marketing energy monitoring and accessible terminals, such as the intelligent
PV control, the energy storage, the charging and discharging control system for the electrical
vehicles, and so on.
So we use these intelligent load devices to achieve the coordinated and optimized operation
for the microgrid.
And we think that the microgrid, the distribution network grid and the main grid will be operated
as a whole audit.
So contractual low voltage network data decision center to equip with internal terminal devices
to carry out advanced applications and gradually achieve power supply automation transparently
of the PV, storage, charging, and digital intelligence distribution and microgrid
coordinated in the distribution transformer area.
So this is our consideration for the three kinds of grid to be operated into our main body.
For the distribution operation, we have developed a lot of intelligent operation maintenance means.
For example, intelligent sensing and the forward direction of the medium voltage distribution switch gap.
We have developed the operating space for the power distribution switch gap.
We use the robot to make an inspection, to make a maintenance for the
huge number of the distribution substations. We make autonomous operations
for the power distribution. We develop a lot of AI technologies to make space.
We make autonomous operation and maintenance systems for power distribution switchguides.
We use the robot to maintain the switch copies.
We have developed intelligent operation, maintenance, and expansion of power distribution switchguides by six degrees of freedom of robotic arms.
They use such kind of intelligent devices to make the maintenance, to make the operation of the huge number of distribution stations.
So that we can ensure the safety operation of the system.
So another phase is the fast protection and self-carrying of the distribution network.
Because, just as what I said in the last part of the lecture, the short-circuit current features, the characteristics of the short-circuit siren have already changed a lot.
Because of the distributed TV, because of the distributed storage, the system has already changed, so the short-circuit current has changed.
So in the past, the protection device based on the traditional operation of the distribution network has already changed.
So we have to develop new kinds of protection devices to protect the short circuit, to protect the outage of the distribution system.
So the first important thing is that we use synchronous measurement and feature extraction
for the four transient signals for power systems, especially for the density power electronic
devices.
So how to make the detection?
So they come with a large scale integration of the distributed PVs to integrate with the distribution network.
So the forward transient signal of the short circuit current has already changed.
So it is urgent to investigate the influence mechanism of the distribution catalogues
on the forward-transiting signal.
So this is very important to develop a new type of protection devices,
because a lot of PV is connected to the system and the signal has changed.
And also, we have to develop very sensitive devices
to make a precise location of the ground fault for the power component based distribution network.
You know that it is very difficult to detect the short circuit, one-phase short circuit,
the circuit to the ground. Such kind of short circuit occurs in the middle of the week.
So it is very difficult to detect such a fault.
especially the large amount of distributed PV to be connected to the system.
So it's very difficult for the operators to develop such a device, such a form.
So how can we develop faster protection devices and self-hearing of the...
And all of these devices are based on the information, on the modern communication technology.
So, we have to take a new intelligent power distribution terminal as a distributed agent.
Fast identification and fast isolation and power transfer.
We have to transfer the non-faulted areas of the supply area into the safety one and isolate the fault.
So all of this based on the new type of communication systems.
So in the third grade, we developed a lot of new type of power distribution terminals.
So such kind of new power distribution terminals include the new technology of Beidou satellite system, especially by the Chinese.
And we have developed chip-based protection.
We have integrated some algorithms into a chip.
And then this kind of protection device can be fast attacked for circuit.
We have developed a very advanced algorithm for the fault perception.
and we use 5th generation, 5th generation of the communication system,
a fast communication system in the distribution system,
to enable the rapid forward location,
to ensure the isolation of the different types,
and to ensure the transfer from the non-forward system,
to fast resume the power supply.
So this picture, all of these pictures are the new devices for the distributed intelligence.
And also we have to ensure the secondary system to be simply operated in the distributed system.
So the secondary system includes the communication system, the protection system,
the data awareness devices, and all of these systems, we call it the secondary system.
So the secondary system is in stock to aim to ensure the safety operation of the main system.
So that this is very, very important for the secondary system safety.
The fourth one is the internal monitoring of the substation and length.
And for the state grid and southern grid, the national grid has developed many inspection
robots to make an intelligent inspection of the substation of the transmission lines to
achieve the reduced manpower inspection and intelligent monitoring of the power grid.
to make the standardized process and to realize the safe and standardized operation for the maintenance, for the inspection, and for the control.
So if you come to the substations, you can see a lot of robots, unmanned inspection devices to be operated in the substations, especially for the high voltage.
And gradually, this kind of high technologies, gradually to be widespread used in the distribution
subdivisions.
So this is the trend, this is the, maybe in the next 5 or 10 years, so this kind of technology
will gradually change, gradually used in the lower voltage systems.
So we think that this is very important for the precise monitoring, the safety operation
for the main power systems, for the distributor system, and finally for the microgrid.
For example, for the transformer, we have a very high attack for the transformer.
Inside the transformer there is a discharge.
So once there is a discharge, you can detect some voice, some change for the oils, several means to detect discharge inside the transformer.
Such a discharge, if we don't process such a fault, maybe the discharge will be suspended to the utilization of the transformer.
So the state grid pays more attention to the discharge inside the transformers.
So the new technology will support the imaging and voice recognition to detect the equipment,
to detect the discharge inside the transformers.
And we use the M-type of the device to be installed in the outside of the transformer and to detect the mean fault of the discharge.
So the voice and the imaging and the recognition technologies could be mixed-used in the detection of the monitoring.
So it can ensure the transformer can be operated safely and to diagnose the minor faults and make the early warning for the transformer.
And for the low-voltage transmission areas, what is the problem we have encountered is that how to make the land loss to be reduced,
because a lot of electricity transmission loss occurred in the low-voltage system.
For the high voltage, the loss is very low, 1% or 2%, but for the low or medium voltage, any loss becomes maybe 6% or 7%.
So how to reduce the land loss is a very serious problem to make the power system to be operated very efficiently.
So, within the same power supply area, we have to install an intelligent transformer
to check the diagonal robot for each transformer to make the diagonal for the land loss, for
the transformer loss, to reduce the loss, either to diagnose what kind of loss could
occur in this area.
One reason is that in the unbalance of the three phase.
Another reason is that the low voltage line is too long, we have to transfer.
And maybe there is some stolen, the electrical stolen.
Maybe some many, many events maybe affect the land loss.
So we have to install the detections to detect, to diagnose what is the loss result for.
The fifth one is the flexible DC interconnection between or among the distributed stations.
You know that many distribution stations are working independently with each other.
They supply their own power supply areas.
They give them power supply to their own users.
So they do not interconnect with each other.
So some of the stations may be overload because of a load increase. So we have to
increase the equipment to expand the capacity of the supply. But some of the
stations, they're less load. But there are a lot of distributed PVs. So we
Rewards transfer from the low voltage to the high voltage.
So this is forbidden for the power grid.
This is not allowed for the power flow
from the low voltage to the high voltage
because it makes the transformer overloaded
to make the voltage to be much higher.
So we have to avoid this.
How to solve this problem?
We use a flexible DC connection.
to link the several distributed stations.
For example, in the left hand, the top hand of the station,
there are two stations.
This is a very successful example.
There are two stations, two turn-voltage stations.
One station is a production area.
They produce oil, oil.
Another substation surprise for the residential areas, there is a lot of distributed TV.
So in this station, there is power voltage.
So the power flow from the lower to the higher one.
For this substation, there is lack of capacity.
capacity. So they have to invest a lot of devices to increase their capacity, to expand
their production to a business. So the two stations could be connected into one. So we
use the interconnected flexible DC, DC to connect the two stations. So the distributed
PV generation could be supplied to the another station to make the balance of the power stations
to reduce the expansion investment for this substation.
And also we solved the discrete PV, they can make the balance of the two stations.
Other things, we use the DC bus bar to connect discharge, charge and discharging EV, electrical
electrical vehicle, to connect the distributed storage to connect to this one, to connect
the distributed TV to this DC bar, so that this is a very successful example for the
change of the flexible DC connections.
So we use such kind of flexible DC interconnection to solve many problems.
For example, the overload of the distributed PV in one substation.
For example, there is a need for the DC busbar to be connected into some distributed PV,
some distributed storage and also we use this kind of interconnected bus bar to
set up a charging station to make a electrical vehicle to be charged or we
have also make a control strategy to make it discharge, to make the charging station to discharge in the peak level.
So we think that the flexo-DC interconnection among the distributed power stations will be widely used in the eastern channel of the distribution network.
So this shows very many advantages for the operation of the distribution network.
Of course, there is a lot of technical problems to be solved for this in the connected distribution.
For example, the mechanism and the modeling, how to model to perform a flexible interconnection.
For example, the flex network control, how to control this flex network.
How to make a dynamic energy support to make the safety for the network with the flexible internet.
how to solve the cross-over, and all of this could be solved by the new technology.
So we have to pay more attention to the technical development for the artificial intelligence technologies.
For example, the AI is a very powerful engine for the production of research and development.
without unmanned helicopter vehicles to be inspected in our system.
The robot version, the AI computing, this AI algorithm to be integrated into the chips,
in the one chip. For example, the application of machine tactile chips for file monitoring
and for the end-story power to prevent the file disaster.
For example, the intelligent identification for the defects of the transmission and distribution lines,
and imaging and adaptive fusion monitoring for the equipment defects,
and for the power environment and so on.
So, so many AI products to be developed in the power system.
And also, we have to pay attention to the many, many applications for the system safety
and prevention, disaster prevention.
For example, the intelligent robot inspection for substations, for example, the health status
detection, and the risk early warning of the on-road chargers, and the early fire warnings
and the file extinguish technology for transformers, for the cables, for the energy storage, and the internal technology for the safety tools.
And the anti-miss operation technology, for example, if someone with a miss, to go into the miss space, there's a warning to tell him that you are wrong.
wrong. So we use the human replacement for the high-risk operations without the
overhead operation. We use the robot to replace the humans as well. So, so many AI
technology to be used in the power system. And the last two things is that we have to pay more
attention to the weather because the weather will affect the new power system
And another thing is that we have to pay attention to the carbon.
So apart from the source, grid, load, and storage operations, apart from this one,
we have to pay attention to the weather, we have to pay attention to the carbon,
because the weather will affect the generation of the renewable energies.
This is a very, very serious program for the operators of the system.
And also, our final objective is to reduce the carbon emission,
to make the power system to be carbon neutral.
So the electricity and the carbon neutralization become very important.
So we have to pay attention to the carbon production and electric carbon production.
So that the safe operation of the new power system would focus on interaction and coordination for the six elements.
The six elements include the source, grid, load, storage, and weather and carbon.
So we think the six elements will make the new type of power system to be operated very safe
and very economical. You know, in the western China, there is a very complex weather.
For example, in Tibet, in Xinjiang, in the western, east-western, in Mongolia,
there is a lot of different conditions, weather conditions, and very complex terrains and landforms.
And this kind of renewable energy generation path, their production, their generation varies very fast with the virus.
So we have to make a global climate change to be identified.
because this global climate change becomes normal.
So we have to count the money, a lot of these things.
So we think that integration of metrology and electric power,
we named metrology power, is impoverished to the power production.
So, with the weather data, with the meteorological data and technology, to be closely linked
with the renewable energy generation forecasting will make the decision of the power grid operation
and the maintenance.
This is very important.
This is an accurate forecast of the renewable energy generation.
This depends on the accurate forecast of the weather, so this is quite important.
And specialized technology for disaster prevention, control, operation and maintenance.
So we have to develop different weather disasters,
such as typhoon forecast, such as tower risk monitoring,
So we have to set up an integrated decision making platform, it will achieve data integration
and effective applications such as weather monitoring, wind, solar, hydropower forecasting
to provide the power sector with 4% services from the early warning to the post-disaster assessment.
So all of these technologies are very urgently needed in the electric power system.
So nowadays we have set up a special committee to do special research on the weather and the electric power,
how to research for the link with each other, especially for the future in the power market.
So if we set up a very complicated power market mechanism,
so the price is very close with the forecast of the generation.
So if you make a missed result, if you make a result that is not very precise,
So we think that deep coupling of the metrology and the electric power is a no-train for the
power security and emergency response.
So in Chinese power system, we have developed some many mini-weather stations.
For example, in Jiangsu province, they are scheduled to install the mini weather stations
every kilometer to detect the weather.
We use the unmanned helicopter with swarm, airborne, cooperative, 3D modeling, and imaging
analysis to inspect the network.
We use emergency plan generation based on large language model.
We have set up a lot of planning.
The people train with the planning into the office.
But if there is an emergency occur, how can we very fast, very quickly,
to respond, to make real, existent planning for the emergency process.
This is dependent on the large language.
We have to develop the emergency plan generation,
automatically generate the emergency planning.
We have to research on the collaborative command
How to organize team, how to organize material, emergency material transportation, and result based on S-train weather forecast.
So all of this is related to the real side of the weather forecast.
This is a very close thing with the policy.
Okay, the last one we have to pay more attention to is carbon.
So the carbon generated by electricity is very very important for the carbon neutral for the new power system.
Because the final organization, the final target of the new power system is to reduce the carbon emission.
So how to calculate the carbon emission for each kilowatt hour of electricity is very important.
So we have a new concept, that is, we make the path.
In the path, we make the source follow the load.
Because if the load changes, we have the order to change the output of the power plant.
This is the traditional operation.
But now this is changed. We changed the load moves with the source.
If the source fluctuates, we make the load to move.
We use our administration policies to encourage the load, the users, to take part in the adjustment.
So load moves with source is very important. This is the demand response.
And also, we promote that load moves with carbon, so through a precise time and region based electricity carbon accounting mechanism,
it is possible to link up with the international carbon tariff system, and to respond to the government carbon reduction policy.
When we make the time-based carbon, each hour, we can track what of this kilowatt hour of electric power generation to be produced in when and where.
When and where the electricity is produced.
So, time-based is the guide to the load to shift to the low-carbon time period, and region-based
is the guide to energy-consuming load to shift to the low-carbon areas.
For example, in the western part of China, there is very low carbon emissions, but our
Our production center is located in the east, how to shift the east and the north to the west.
So this is very important.
So lower the force of carbon will inevitably lead to significant change in the planning, in the construction, in the operation of the power system.
And it will show an important impact on the great architecture, the safety operation of the west to east power transmission in China.
So we have another idea, we will transfer the lower centers, the lower consumption from the eastward, to the lower carbon area.
So the United States made a proposal that we make the carbon production calculations by time, from annually to hourly.
So each hour, they will publish, they will announce which of the electricity produced by what time, by where, where they are.
So this goes from Swiss, to country Swiss, to a balance space, to a load center, to a load zone.
So this is the United States' suggestion, the standard.
And also, the United Congress requires the EIA to publish hourly average carbon emission
factors for each electric power utility.
So you can check in the website, you can check, for example, you can check the American utility,
they will announce their electric power production produced in which area in what time.
So this is very important to track the carbon prints.
So we have focused first to establish an international recognized carbon footprint
to print on the carbon standard certification system and to create a fair and equitable international carbon printing management.
This is very important for us to set up such a system.
For our side, for our team, we are now constructing a single electricity carbon map based on big data.
so the electricity carbon map this is a very very complex model from the
electric power grid to the production data and then we calculate the carbon
flow along with the network and finally we make each each point each electric
point, they produce, they will supply the electricity, and we give index for each kilowatt
hour. And finally we want to make every product a signal. If you scan the signal, you can
know that how many carbon emissions come from this product and when and where this product is produced
how many kilowatt hours consumed to produce this product so that we can make a very very detailed
detection so we think the integrated map is very important so we make the optimize of the six
elements, source, grid, load, storage and weather and carbon to support the safety
operation of our city. To make a clean and low carbon production, to make a safety
margin, to make a economic efficient operation, to make a supply-demand
coordination and response, to make a flexible and smart operation. So this
This is a simple description of our system.
First of all, we collect a lot of data.
Weather data, information data, detection data, and so on.
We make the knowledge base, we make the research center,
enhance the generation, and so on.
We make the dark model for the detection center.
So that we can develop a predictive dark model.
and some weather large models, and so on.
And finally, we take a technological base
based on the graph analysis, graph knowledge and calculations.
And we use this database to support
source load prediction, to support carbon footprint
measurement, to support the situation
awareness, to support the planetary magnification,
to support collaborative optimization, to support flexibility optimization, and so on.
So this kind of big data system is very useful for the future advanced operations of the new power system.
So we use this map, and we set up a graph technology foundation.
This is the support, this is the basic information.
And we make some AI-influenced decision making.
This is the software.
And finally, we make an electrical carbon coupling on that.
And how about carbon?
carbon. You see, this kind of data system, for the power system operation, and for the comprehensive and accurate
weather power generation, load forecasting, use this because of fused weather data, AI based process
predictions. And for the online security assessment for the power system, with those great load storage,
Why the carbon benefit? So that we can analyze, how about this power system, you have, whether there is a magic for the power system to expand, whether there is a magic to interconnect with the PVs and so on.
And also, we can make an analysis of grid adequacy and flexibility based on the six sectors.
For example, for this kind of a system, how to connect, how many distributed PV could be connected to the system.
So, finally, we make a report for the provincial detection contracts.
And these project centers integrate multi-source systems, including data type and intraday power generation plants,
including new energy power and load forecasting, including virtual power plants,
and to build an integrated automation platform in provincial infrastructure centers
for the source with load storage devices and commons for the sector.
So this is our government support project, we are now setting up such a platform in Guangxi province.
Okay, thank you. Any questions?
Any questions? No questions?
I just want to know how long did it take you to implement all of those in China?
This project is not ongoing. It's not completed.
Because the project is set up the year before last.